MIN-CHEN LIN

UX & SERVICE DESIGNER



NATIONALITY

Taiwan / Holder of Dutch residence and work permit



Cocation

The Netherlands / Amsterdam



■ PORTFOLIO WEBSITE

https://minchen-lin.gi thub.io/

CONTACT

minchen.lin.1216@ gmail.com



augua1216



www.linkedin.com/in/ minchen-lin



+31-(0)6-38957128



EXPERTISE

User Interface Design

User Research

Service Design

Business Innovation

METHODOLOGIES / Tools

Design Thinking

Persona

Contextual Inquiry

Affinity Diagram

Customer Journey Map

Service Blueprint

Business Model Canvas

Value Proposition Canvas

PROFILE

A passionate and experienced UXUI and Service Designer with 5 years of practical experience in this field, who is trained by diverse projects in Taiwan and in Germany. With my Information and Service Design background, I have systematic thinking with business consideration, and like to be a voracious problem solver.

As a senior designer in an international company, I am always the main communicator/planner in a multicultural/functional teams, which has been exciting for me and meets my proactive personality perfectly.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Trend Micro | Senior UXUI designer (Taiwan, 05/2016 - 05/2019)

- · Oversee company strategies to plan the design roadmap and encourage the team to look forward.
- · Lead end-to-end product design on web applications, which need to collaborate closely with multicultural and multidisciplinary teams to fulfill the goal.
- · Conduct qualitative (job shadowing, interviews and workshops) and quantitative (user behavior data anayzing with Tableau and Matomo) researches to dive into user needs.
- · Main Products: Trend Micro Endpoint Sensor (Endpoint detection and response solutions), Threat Investigation Center (Remote incident response solutions)

Delta Electronics | Design Engineer (Taiwan, 01/2015 - 05/2016)

- · Conducted field studies and contextual inquiry to empathy potential users and expose real reasons/core issues behind their motivations and actions.
- · Designed user interfaces and a service modal based on research results, business requirements, and with consideration of technical feasibility.

SKILLS

Axure

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe Photoshop

Mogups

Sketch

HTML

CSS

LANGUAGE

Mandarin

Native speaker

English

TOEIC 860 | Fluent

German

B1 | Basic

INTERESTS

Drawing

Reading



(https://minchen-lin.gith ub.io/illustration.html)



Traveling

Love being a backpacker



Biking



Front end development My portfolio website is mostly done by myself



- Delivered high-quality visual presentation for the biggest annually demos.
- · Main Products: Building Surveillance, Pet-care Service
- Tool Used: Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Moqups

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Hospital Hygiene | Service Designer (Germany, 05/2014 - 07/2014)

- · Led by Prof. Brigit Mager (president of Service Design Network). Identified main challenges of German health system and developed innovation concepts for this service domain.
- · Took the ownership of "Encouragement", and developed three ideas for increasing cleaners' sense of belonging in the hospital.

Deutsche Telekom Case Competition | System Designer (Germany, 01/2014 - 02/2014)

- · Designed a new service with Machine-to-Machine (M2M) technique targeting B2B business model. Our proposal: DREAM2M-AVEL is focusing on the issue of insufficient water in Africa.
- · Stood out from other groups and be invited to Telekom headquarters for the final presentation.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Design Thinking Club | Core Member/Facilitator (Taiwan, 2012 - 2013)

· Hosted a Design Thinking workshop for NeuroSky (http://neurosky.com/) with 30 participants based on Biosensor Technology to develop new applications.

University Basketball Club | Captain (Taiwan, 2008 - 2010)

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration in Service Science (National Tsing-Hua University| Taiwan, 2011 - 2014)

· Focus on issues in technology-enabled and knowledge intensive Service Design/Service Innovation.



Business Administration

(RWTH Aachen University | Germany, 2013 - 2014)

Service Design

(Köln International School of Design | Germany, 2013 - 2014)

Bachelor of Information Management

(National Central University | Taiwan, 2007 - 2011)